Guide to the Henry Charlton Bastian papers, 1841-1932 and undated, bulk 1870-1920
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Correspondence Series, 1856-1932 and undated, bulk 1870-1920, (3 boxes)
  - Alcan, Félix: 2 typed letters signed to Bastian concerning the French translation of The Evolution of Life. 4 pp. total, plus 1 cover, 1907 Feb. 19 (Box 2)
  - Methuen & Co.: Typed letter signed to Bastian, with Bastian's note at the foot dated 2/9/07. 1 page, 1907 Feb. 19 (Box 2)
  - Mattino(?), V.: Autograph letter signed to Bastian. 2 pp., 1907 Feb. 21 (Box 2)
  - Methuen & Co.: Typed letter signed to Bastian concerning illustrations. 1 page, 1907 Feb. 23 (Box 2)
  - Alcan, Félix: Typed letter signed to Bastian. 1 page, 1907 Mar. 25 (Box 2)
  - Alcan, Félix: Autograph letter signed to Bastian. 2 pp., 1907 Apr. 3 (Box 2)
  - Alcan, Félix: Typed letter signed to Bastian negotiating terms. 2 pp., 1907 Apr. 10 (Box 2)
  - Alcan, Félix: Autograph letter signed to Bastian, plus typed contract signed by Bastian and Alcan, re publication of a French edition of The Evolution of Life. 3 pp., 1907 Apr. 17 (Box 2)
  - Jarvis, Stephen Eyre: Autograph letter signed to Bastian discussing abiogenesis. 2 pp., 1907 Apr. 21 (Box 2)
  - Loewenthal, Max: Autograph letter signed to Bastian concerning The Evolution of Life. 4 pp., 1907 Apr. 25 (Box 2)
  - [---]: Autograph letter signed to Max. 1 page, 1907 Apr. 30 (Box 2)
  - Casalegno, B.; Hans Rinck: 2 autograph letters signed to Bastian concerning an Italian translation of The Evolution of Life plus blank postcard. 2 pp., 1907 Apr. 6 (Box 2)
  - Gradenwitz, Alfred. Tarrida del: Typed letter signed to Bastian. 1 page, 1907 May 30 (Box 2)
  - Gradenwitz, Alfred: Typed letter signed to Bastian. 1 page, 1907 July 1 (Box 2)
  - Seaton, Edward: Autograph letter signed to Bastian discussing abiogenesis. 4 pp., 1907 July 18 (Box 2)
  - Walker, Jane: Autograph letter signed to Bastian, with autograph letter signed to Bastian enclosing Walker's letter. 3 pp., 1907 July 25 (Box 2)
  - Seaton(?), Edward: Autograph letter to Bastian. 1 page, 1907 July 31 (Box 2)
  - Methuen & Co.: letter acknowledging Bastian's new address. 1 page, 1907 Aug. 6 (Box 2)
  - Strachan-Davidson, James L.: Autographed letter to Sybil Bastian, 1 page, 1907 Aug. 19 (Box 2)
  - Duncan, Robert Kennedy: Autograph letter signed to Mrs. Bastian. 2 pp., 1907 Aug. 28 (Box 2)
  - Maxwell, W. H.: 2 autograph notes signed to Bastian concerning Bastian's work. 4 pp., 1907 Sept. 4 (Box 2)
  - Methuen & Co.: Statement of account for The Evolution of Life. 1 sheet, 1907 Nov. (Box 2)
  - Hewlett, R. T.: Autograph letter signed to Bastian. 1 page, 1907 Dec. 3 (Box 2)
  - Reid, F. J.: Autograph letter signed to Bastian. 2 pp., 1907 Dec. 15 (Box 2)
  - Dunbar, Dr.: Autograph letter signed to Bastian discussing bacteriology. 3 pp., 1908 Jan. 12th (Box 2)
  - Reid, F. J.: Autograph letter signed to Bastian concerning abiogenesis experiments. 4 pp., 1908 Apr. 10 (Box 2)
  - Methuen & Co.: Statement of account for The Evolution of Life. 1 page, 1908 May (Box 2)
  - Dunbar, Dr.: Autograph letter signed to Bastian discussing bacteriology. 2+ pp., 1908 Aug. 2 (Box 2)
  - Dunbar, Dr.: Autograph letter signed to Bastian discussing bacteriology. 1 page, 1908 Oct. 8 (Box 2)
  - Boyce, Robert: Letter signed to Bastian. 2 pp., 1908 Nov. 25 (Box 2)
  - Methuen & Co.: Statement of account for The Evolution of Life. 1 page, 1908 Nov. (Box 2)
  - T. Fisher Unwin: Typed letter signed to Bastian concerning The Nature and Origin of Living Matter, with Bastian's handwritten notes. 1 page, 1908 Dec. 29 (Box 2)
  - Tozer, Eustace: Correspondence with Bastian concerning abiogenesis. 6 pieces, 1909 Jan. 5 (Box 2)
  - Warren, T. Herbert: Typed letter signed to Bastian concerning Herbert Spencer lectureship at Magdalen College. 1 page, 1909 Mar. 27 (Box 2)
  - Watts, Charles A.: Typed letter signed to Bastian. 1 page, 1909 Apr. 26 (Box 2)
  - Methuen & Co.: Accounting document concerning The Evolution of Life. 1 page, 1909 May (Box 2)
  - Barlow, Thomas: Autograph postcard signed to Miss Bastian, 1910 Apr. 27 (Box 2)
  - Pratelle, Aristide: Autograph letter signed to Bastian, plus cutting of Pratelle's review of The Nature and Origin of Living Matter. 6 pp., 1910 July 13 (Box 2)
  - Mary, Albert and Alexandre: 2 letters signed to Bastian (July 14 and Aug. 4). 2pp., 1910 July 14 (Box 2)
  - Mary, Albert and Alexandre: Letter signed to Bastian, Outline of a report after a demonstration. 6 pp., 1910 July 16 (Box 2)
    Albert and Alexandre Mary, proprietors of Laboratoire Mary at the Institut de Biophysique, performed scientific work for Bastian in his abiogenesis research.
  - Duncan, Robert Kennedy: 2 typed letters signed to Bastian (Mar. 20 and Apr. 25) concerning setting up an abiogenesis research program. 2 pp., 1911 Mar. 20 (Box 2)
  - Carrel, F.: Autograph letter signed to Bastian concerning The Origin of Life. 4 pp., 1911 Apr. 20 (Box 2)
  - G. P. Putnam's Sons: Typed letter signed (by C. Huntington) to Bastian concerning royalties for American edition of Origin of Life. 1 page, 1911 Apr. 29 (Box 2)
  - Marmol, F. Tarrida del: Autograph letter signed to Bastian mentioning Bastian's publications on abiogenesis. 2 pp., 1911 Apr. 30 (Box 2)
  - Pratelle, Aristide: 2 autograph letters signed to Bastian (June 21 and Oct. 10), plus page of Bastian's notes. 7 pp., 1911 June 21 (Box 2)
  - G. P. Putnam's Sons: Typed letter signed (by C. Huntington) to Bastian concerning American edition of Origin of Life. 2 pp., 1911 July 10 (Box 2)
  - G. P. Putnam's Sons: Typed letter signed (by C. Huntington) to Bastian concerning American edition of The Evolution of Life. 1 page, 1911 Oct. 25 (Box 2)
  - G. P. Putnam's Sons: Typed letter signed (by C. Huntington) to Bastian concerning American edition of The Evolution of Life. 1 page, 1911 Nov. 20 (Box 2)
  - Hewlett, R.T.; Bastian: Correspondence between Hewlett and Bastian regarding abiogenesis research. 5 pieces, including 4 letters from Hewlett (one with cover) and one from Bastian, 1910-1911 (Box 2)
  - Lamertin, Henri; L. Guinet: Correspondence concerning French translation of The Origin of Life. 4 pieces, 1911-1913 (Box 2)
  - Mary, Albert and Alexandre: Letter signed to Bastian. 1 page, 1912 Feb. 28 (Box 2)
  - Russell, Charles: Autograph letter signed to Mrs. Bastian. 2 pp., 1912 Mar. 24 (Box 2)
  - Tate, J. E.: Autograph letter signed to Bastian concerning abiogenesis. 4 pp., 1912 Apr. 28 (Box 2)
  - G. P. Putnam's Sons: 4 typewritten American copyright statements for Bastian's The Origin of Life. 4 sheets plus 1 cover, 1912-1913 May 1 (Box 2)
  - Grasset, Hector: 2 autograph letters signed to Bastian. 2+ pp., 1912 June 5 (Box 2)
  - Grasset, Hector: Autograph letter signed to Bastian. 2 pp., 1912 June 13 (Box 2)
  - Grasset, Hector: Autograph letter signed to Bastian. 5+ pp., 1912 June 23 (Box 2)
  - Grasset, Hector: Autograph letter signed to Bastian. 2 pp., 1912 June 27 (Box 2)
  - Mary, Albert and Alexandre: Letter signed to Bastian concerning publishing his work. 2 pp., 1912 Aug. 3 (Box 2)
  - Grasset, Hector: Autograph letter signed to Bastian. 1 page, 1912 July 20 (Box 2)
  - Grasset, Hector: Autograph letter signed to Bastian. 1 page plus cover; Bastian's notes on cover, 1912 Sept. 13th (Box 2)
  - Moore, Benjamin: Autograph letter signed to Bastian concerning abiogenesis. 5 pp., 1912 Sept. 23 (Box 2)
  - Stevenson, A. C.: Autograph note signed to Bastian. 1 page, 1912 Oct. 3 (Box 2)
  - Mary, Albert and Alexandre: Letter signed to Bastian concerning La synth& du bacille de Koch. 2 pp., 1912 Dec. 18 (Box 2)
  - Whytlaw-Gray, R.: Autograph letter signed to Bastian concerning experiments. 1 page, 1912 Dec. 12 (Box 2)
  - Whytlaw-Gray, R: Autograph letter signed to Bastian concerning experiments. 1 page, 1912 Dec. 20 (Box 2)
  - Massee, George: Autograph letter signed to Bastian concerning abiogenesis. 2 pp., 1912 Dec. 26 (Box 2)
  - Bastian; A. G. Stevenson; Sir William Ramsay: Carbon copies (or transcripts) of typed correspondence between Bastian, Stevenson and Ramsay regarding Bastian's abiogenesis experiments. 11 pp., 1912 (Box 2)
  - Hill, Arthur W.: Autograph letter signed to Bastian concerning fungus spores. 1 page, 1913 Jan. 15 (Box 2)
  - Mary, Albert and Alexandre: Letter signed to Bastian. 1 page plus cover (defective), 1913 Jan. 20 (Box 2)
  - Ross, H. C.: Autograph letter signed to Bastian, mentioning Ray Lankester. 2+ pp., 1913 Jan. 27 (Box 2)
  - Barlow, Thomas: Autograph letter signed to Bastian. 2 pp., 1913 Jan. 28 (Box 2)
  - Ross, H. C.: Autograph letter signed to Bastian discussing experiments. 2 pp., 1913 Feb. 6 (Box 2)
  - Farmer, John Bretland: Autograph letter signed to Bastian. 3 pp., 1913 Feb. 27 (Box 2)
  - Farmer, John Bretland: Autograph letter signed to Bastian concerning abiogenesis experiments. 2 pp., 1913 Mar. 12 (Box 2)
  - Duke, W.(?): Autograph letter to Miss Bastian, 1 page, 1913 Mar. 24 (Box 2)
  - Farmer, John Bretland: Autograph letter signed to Bastian concerning abiogenesis experiments — oospora. 2 pp., 1913 Apr. 3 (Box 2)
  - Mary, Albert and Alexandre: Letter signed to Bastian. 3 pp., 1913 Apr. 15 (Box 2)
  - Harrison, Austin: Autograph letter to Bastian. 1 page, 1913 Apr. 28 (Box 2)
  - Guinet, L.: Autograph postcard signed to Bastian, 1913 May 3 (Box 2)
  - Delfino, Victor: Typed letter signed to William Bastian from editor of La Semana Medica concerning biographical notice and portrait of Bastian. 1 page, 1913 May 8 (Box 2)
  - Buzzard, W.(?): Autographed letter to Sybil Bastian. 1 page, 1913 May 19 (Box 2)
  - Delfino, Victor: Typed letter signed to Bastian (waterstained). 1 page, 1913 May 23 (Box 2)
  - Moore, Benjamin: Autograph letter signed to Bastian concerning abiogenesis research. 4 pp., 1913 June 10 (Box 2)
  - Moore, Benjamin: Autograph letter signed to Bastian concerning abiogenesis research. 2 pp., 1913 June 21 (Box 2)
  - Herrera, A. L.: Autograph postcard signed to Bastian, 1913 July 22 (Box 2)
  - Damianovich, H.: 2 autograph letters signed to Bastian. 4 pp., 1913 July 24 (Box 2)
  - Moore, Benjamin: Autograph letter signed to Bastian concerning abiogenesis research. 2 pp., 1913 Aug. 1 (Box 2)
  - Meauseu(?), C.: Autograph letter in French on Revue Scientifique letterhead, 1913 Aug. 14 (Box 2)
  - Collings, C. H.: Typed letter signed to Bastian concerning abiogenesis. 5 pp., 1913 Aug. 21 (Box 2)
  - Mary, Albert and Alexandre: Letter signed to Bastian. 2 pp., 1913 Aug. 30 (Box 2)
  - Mary, Albert and Alexandre: Letter signed to Bastian. 4 pp., 1913 Sept. 17 (Box 2)
  - Marmol, F. T. del: Autograph letter signed to Bastian from editor of Fray Mocho (Buenos Aires). 1 page, 1913 Oct. 14 (Box 2)
  - Dreaper, W. P.: Typed letter signed to Bastian. 1 page, 1913 Oct. 16 (Box 2)
  - Moore, Benjamin: Autograph letter signed to Bastian mentioning abiogenesis experiments. 4 pp., 1913 Oct. 30 (Box 2)
  - Hatscher, Emil: Typed letter signed to Bastian concerning silicic acid solution. 1 page, 1913 Nov. 7 (Box 2)
  - Charbonnel, Victor: Typed letter signed to Bastian. 1 page, 1913 Dec. 31 (Box 2)
  - Ker, William Paton: 6 autograph letters signed to Sybil Bastian. 10 pp. total, 1913-1920 (Box 3)
  - Mary, Albert and Alexandre: Letter signed to Bastian, together with 9 photomicrographs annotated on the versos in Bastian's hand. 2 pp., 1913 (Box 3)
  - Tozer, Eustace: Autograph letter signed to Bastian concerning heterogenesis. 4 pp., 1914 Jan. 31 (Box 3)
  - Collie, J. N.: Autograph letter signed to Bastian. 2+ pp., 1914 Feb. 4 (Box 3)
  - Onslow, H.: Typed letter signed to Bastian. 1 page, 1914 Feb. 5 (Box 3)
  - Rosenheim, O.: Autograph letter signed to Bastian. 2 pp., 1914 Feb. 17 (Box 3)
  - Pratelle, Aristide: 2 autograph letters signed to Bastian, one mentioning Albert Mary. 1914 Mar. 18 (Box 3)
  - Hickson(?), [---]: Autograph letter to Bastian, 1914 Mar. 19 (Box 3)
  - Hatschek, Emil: Typed letter signed to Bastian concerning silicic acid solution. 1 page, 1914 Mar. 28 (Box 3)
  - Ker, W: Autograph letter to S. Bastian, 2 pp., 1914 Apr. 6 (Box 3)
  - Reid, F. J.: Autograph letter to S. Bastian, 3 pp.,, 1914 Apr. 9 (Box 3)
  - Delfino, Victor: Typed letter signed to Bastian concerning translation of The Evolution of Life. 1 page, 1914 May 7 (Box 3)
  - Saleeby, Caleb Williams: Autograph postcard signed to Bastian concerning Saleeby's The Origin of Bacteria, 1914 May 23 (Box 3)
  - Lightbown, Constance M.: Autograph letter signed to Bastian from Honorable Secretary of the Manchester University Biological Society. 1 page, 1914 June 6 (Box 3)
  - Delfino, Victor: Typed letter signed to Bastian concerning Spanish translation of The Evolution of Life. 1 page, 1914 July 12 (Box 3)
  - [---]: Autograph letter to Wolfram, from Wyndham's Theatre, London, 1914 Sept. 28 (Box 3)
  - Nobel Committee (Medical): Form letter from the committee to Bastian, plus enclosed list of previous prize winners in physiology/medicine. 3 pp. total, 1914 Sept. (Box 3)
  - Drew, Aubrey H.: Typed letter signed concerning abiogenesis experiments. 2 pp., 1914 Oct. 27 (Box 3)
  - Rosenheim, O.: Autograph letter signed to Bastian mentioning Bastian's abiogenesis work. 2 pp., 1914 Dec. 28 (Box 3)
  - Kennedy, Alex: Autograph letter to Sybil Bastian, 1 page, 1914 Dec. 28 (Box 3)
  - Wright, Jonathan: Typed letter signed to Bastian concerning abiogenesis experiments. 1 page, 1914 Dec. 29 (Box 3)
  - Drew, Aubrey: Autograph postcard signed to Bastian, mentioning experiments, 1914 Dec. 30 (Box 3)
  - Mary, Albert: Letter signed to Bastian. 2 pp., 1914 Dec. 31 (Box 3)
  - Damianovich, H.: Autograph letter signed to Bastian regarding abiogenesis research, with 3 photomicrographs enclosed (annotations by Damianovich on versos). 4 pp., 1915 (Box 3)
  - Mary, Albert and Alexandre: Letter signed to Bastian. 2 pp., 1915 Jan. 22 (Box 3)
  - Mary, Albert and Alexandre; Bastian: Typed English translation of letter of Jan. 22 to Bastian. 4+ pp., 1915 Jan. 22 (Box 3)
  - Reid, F. J.: Autograph letter signed to Bastian concerning abiogenesis experiments, with drawings. 4 pp., 1915 Jan. 29 (Box 3)
  - Mary, Albert and Alexandre: 2 letters signed to Bastian. 2 pp., 1915 Jan. 31 (Box 3)
  - Cropper, J. W.: Autograph letter signed to Bastian concerning abiogenesis research. 2 pp., 1915 Feb. 2 (Box 3)
  - Cropper, J. W.: Autograph letter signed to Bastian concerning abiogenesis experiments. 3 pp., 1915 Feb. 12 (Box 3)
  - Reid, F. J.: Autograph letter signed to Bastian concerning abiogenesis research. 2 pp., 1915 Feb. 19 (Box 3)
  - Cropper, J. W.: Autograph letter signed to Bastian concerning abiogenesis experiments. 2 pp., 1915 Feb. 22 (Box 3)
  - Tedder, Henry R.: Typed letter signed to Bastian. 1 page, 1915 Feb. (Box 3)
  - Farmer, John Bretland: Autograph letter signed to Bastian concerning abiogenesis work. 3 pp., 1915 Mar. 16 (Box 3)
  - Green, A. S.: Three autograph postcards to S. Bastian, 1915 Mar. 30 (Box 3)
  - Onslow, H.: Typed letter signed to Bastian. 1 page, 1915 Apr. 3 (Box 3)
  - Massee, George: Autograph letter signed to Bastian concerning abiogenesis experiments. 2 pp., 1915 Apr. 13 (Box 3)
  - Ledingham, John Charles Grant: Autograph note signed to Bastian, on letterhead of the Lister Institute of Preventive Medicine. 1 page, 1915 May 7 (Box 3)
  - Delfino, Victor: Typed letter signed to Bastian mentioning Spanish translation of The Evolution of Life. 1 page, 1915 May 31 (Box 3)
  - Onslow, H.: Typed letter with stamped signature. 1 page, 1915 June 11 (Box 3)
  - Duncan, D.: Autograph letter signed to Bastian. 2 pp., 1915 June 17 (Box 3)
  - Duncan, D.: Autograph letter signed to Bastian. 2 pp., 1915 July 1 (Box 3)
  - Fry, Edward: Postcard to Bastian in the hand of M. F., 1915 July 6 (Box 3)
  - Mary, Albert and Alexandre: 2 letters signed to Bastian. 4 pp. total, 1915 July 17 (Box 3)
  - Mary, Albert and Alexandre: Letter signed to Bastian, with enclosed note from M. Perrier of the Institut de France. 3 pp. plus cover. Letter includes drawing of microorganisms, 1915 July 20 (Box 3)
  - Pratelle, Aristide: Autograph postcard signed to Bastian, 1915 Aug. 2 (Box 3)
  - Tedder, Henry R.: Printed form letter, completed in Tedder's hand, to Bastian. 1 page, 1915 Aug. 20 (Box 3)
  - Tedder, Henry R.: Typed letter signed to Bastian. 1+ page, 1915 Sept. 11 (Box 3)
  - Drew, Aubrey: Autograph letter signed to Bastian discussing hay infusion experiments. 1+ pages, 1915 Sept. 18 (Box 3)
  - Hewlett, R. J: Autograph letter to S. Bastian. 2 pp., 1915 Sept. 26 (Box 3)
  - Fennetier, Georges: Autograph letter signed to Bastian. 2 pp., 1915 Oct. 18 (Box 3)
  - Voelcker, Arthur Francis: Autograph letter of condolence signed to Mrs. Bastian. 3 pp., 1915 Nov. 19 (Box 3)
  - Berkart, J. B.: Autograph letter of condolence, signed, to Mrs. Bastian. 1 page, 1915 Nov. 19 (Box 3)
  - Mott(?), Frederick: Autograph letter of condolence, signed, to Mrs. Bastian. 1 page, 1915 Nov. 19 (Box 3)
  - Hewlett, R. T.: Autograph letter of condolence to Mrs. Bastian, 2 pp., 1915 Nov. 19 (Box 3)
  - Elliot, Hugh: Autograph letter of condolence, signed, to Miss Bastian. 2+ pp., 1915 Nov. 19 (Box 3)
  - Tedder, Henry R.: Typed letter of condolence signed to Miss Bastian. 1+ page, 1915 Nov. 20 (Box 3)
  - Duncan, D.: Autograph condolence letter signed to Sybil Bastian. 3+ pages, 1915 Nov. 20 (Box 3)
  - Bradford, John: Autograph letter of condolence to Mrs. Bastian. 1 page, 1915 Nov. 21 (Box 3)
  - Duncan, D.: Autograph letter of condolence signed to Sybil Bastian. 3+ pages, 1915 Nov. 21 (Box 3)
  - Shaw-Mackenzie, J. G.: Autograph letter of condolence to Miss Bastian. 3 pp., 1915 Nov. 22 (Box 3)
  - Lockyer, J. Norman: Letter of condolence signed to Mrs. Bastian. 3 pp., 1915 Nov. 22 (Box 3)
  - Roberts, Frederick: Autograph letter of condolence signed to Mrs. Bastian. 2 pp., 1915 Nov. 22 (Box 3)
  - Barker(?), Arthur: Autograph letter of condolence signed to Mrs. Bastian, 3 pp., 1915 Nov. 23 (Box 3)
  - Wilberforce, Basil: Autograph note signed to Mrs. Bastian, 1915 Nov. 25 (Box 3)
  - Shaw, [---]: Autograph letter of condolence signed to Mrs. Bastian, 1915 Nov. 25 (Box 3)
  - Buckle, J. Gerald: Typed condolence letter signed to Mrs. Bastian. 1 page, 1915 Nov. 26 (Box 3)
  - Macmillan, Frederick: Autograph letter of condolence signed to Mrs. Bastian. 1 page, 1915 Nov. 27 (Box 3)
  - Mary, Albert & Alexandre: Autograph letter of condolence signed to Miss Bastian. 1 page, 1915 Dec. 13 (Box 3)
  - University College Hospital: Letter of condolence to Mrs. Bastian. 1 page, 1915 Dec. 15 (Box 3)
  - Pratelle, Aristide: Autograph letter of condolence signed to Bastian's family; also discusses French edition of The Origin of Living Matter. 1 page, 1915 Dec. 26 (Box 3)
  - Kennedy, Alex: Autograph letter signed to Miss Bastian. 2 pp., 1916 Jan. 2 (Box 3)
  - Green(?), S.: Autograph letter signed to Miss Bastian, 1916 Jan. 11 (Box 3)
  - Mary, Albert: Letter signed to Sybil Bastian. 1 page, 1916 Jan. 19 (Box 3)
  - Tedder, Henry R.: Typed letter signed to Miss Bastian. 1 page, 1916 Feb. 4 (Box 3)
  - Rationalist Press Association: Typed letter, signed by Charles A. Watts, to Sybil Bastian. 1 page, 1916 Feb. 7 (Box 3)
  - Tedder, Henry R.: Autograph letter signed to Miss Bastian. 1 page, 1916 Feb. 12 (Box 3)
  - Soriano, Manuel F.: Typed letter with stamped signature to Bastian from the Boletin de Ciencias Medicas (Mexico). 1 page, 1916 Feb. 14 (Box 3)
  - Mary, Albert: Letter signed to Sybil Bastian. 1 page, 1916 Feb. 16 (Box 3)
  - Pratelle, Aristide: Autograph letter signed to Sybil Bastian. 1 page, 1916 Feb. 17 (Box 3)
  - Tedder, Henry R.: Autograph letter signed to Miss Bastian. 1 page, 1916 Feb. 19 (Box 3)
  - Watts, Charles: Autograph postcard to Sybil Bastian. 1916 Apr. 2 (Box 3)
  - Tedder, Henry R.: Autograph letter signed to Miss Bastian. 1 page, 1916 Apr. 15 (Box 3)
  - Tedder, Henry R.: Typed letter signed to Miss Bastian. 1 page, 1916 Apr. 19 (Box 3)
  - Tedder, Henry R.: Autograph letter signed to Miss Bastian. 1 page, 1916 June 22 (Box 3)
  - Ross, Ronald: Autograph postcard signed to Staff Surgeon Bastian R.N. (not HCB), 1916 July 30 (Box 3)
  - Duncan, D: Autograph letter signed to Miss Bastian. 4 pp., 1916 Oct. 26 (Box 3)
  - Tedder, Henry R.: Typed letter signed to Miss Bastian. 1 page, 1916 Oct. 30 (Box 3)
  - Tedder, Henry R.: Typed letter signed to Miss Bastian. 1 page, 1916 Nov. 7 (Box 3)
  - Bollan(?), C.: Autograph letter signed to Miss Bastian. 2 pp., 1917 Feb. 13 (Box 3)
  - Punch Office: Autograph letter signed to Miss Bastian, 1 page, 1917 June 17 (Box 3)
  - Mott, F. W.: Autograph letter signed to Mrs. Bastian, 1 page, 1917 June 30 (Box 3)
  - Lowe, Harford J.: Autograph letter signed to Mr. Fox, mentioning Bastian's work on abiogenesis. 1 page, 1917 Oct. 3 (Box 3)
  - Mott, F. W.: Autograph letter signed to Mrs. Bastian, 2 pp., 1917 Oct. 8 (Box 3)
  - Ker, W.: Autograph letter signed to Sybil. 1 page, 1917 Oct. 31 (Box 3)
  - Mary, Albert: Autograph postcard signed to Miss Bastian, 1917 Dec. 30 (Box 3)
  - Mary, Albert: Autograph postcard signed to William Bastian, 1920 May 3 (Box 3)
  - Ker, W.: Autograph postcard signed to Miss Bastian, 1920 Mar. 3 (Box 3)
  - [---], Louise: Autograph letter to Sybil, 1922 July 10 (Box 3)
  - G. P. Putnam's Sons: Typed letter signed to S. Bastian concerning Origin of Life. 1 page, 1923 Oct. 16 (Box 3)
  - [---]: Autograph postcard signed to Miss Bastian, 1923 Sept. 24 (Box 3)
  - Gamey(?), [---]: Autograph letter signed to Sybil Bastian. 4 pp., 1924 Nov. 27 (Box 3)
  - Rolleston, Humphrey: 2 typed postcards signed to Miss Bastian, 1925 Jan. 12 (Box 3)
  - Robertson, J. F.: Autograph letter signed to Sybil Bastian. 2 pp., 1925 Nov. 22 (Box 3)
  - Milice, Albert: Autograph letter signed, presumably to Sybil Bastian. 1+ pp., 1926 June 19 (Box 3)
  - Haynes, E. S. P.: Autograph letter signed to Sybil Bastian. 2 pp., 1928 July 6 (Box 3)
  - Busk, [---]: Autograph letter signed to Sybil Bastian. 2 pp., 1928 Oct. 17 (Box 3)
  - Haynes, Edmund Sidney Pollock: Autograph letter signed to Sybil Bastian. 2 pp., 1928 Oct. 19 (Box 3)
  - [---]: Autograph letter signed to Sybil. 2 pp., 1932 July 24 (Box 3)
  - Barlow, Thomas: Autograph letter signed to Miss Bastian. 2 pp., undated (Box 3)
  - Broadbent, Mrs.: Autograph letter signed to Bastian, with enclosure, undated (Box 3)
  - Cocks, William Pennington: (Portion of?) autograph letter signed. 2 pp., undated (Box 3)
  - Farmer, John Bretland: Autograph letter signed to Bastian mentioning colloidal silica. 2+ pp., undated but probably 1913 (Box 3)
  - Farmer, John Bretland: Autograph letter signed to Bastian. 2 pp., undated (Box 3)
  - Fennetier, Georges: Autograph letter signed, on letterhead of the Museum d’Histoire Naturelle de Rouen. 1 sheet, undated (Box 3)
  - Fleury, G.: Autograph letter signed to Bastian. 2+ pps., undated (Box 3)
  - Foster, B. Walter: Autograph letter signed to Bastian thanking him for Paralyses Cerebral Bulbar and Spinal. Undated but probably 1886 (Box 3)
  - Fox, D[--]: Autograph letter signed to Bastian thanking him for copy of his work on paralysis. 1 page, undated (Box 3)
  - Gratteville(?), Jos.: Autograph letter signed to Bastian. 2 pp., undated (Box 3)
  - Green, Alice S.: 3 autograph notes signed to Miss Bastian, undated (Box 3)
  - Haynes, E. S. P.: Autograph letter signed to Bastian, mentioning Haynes's Belief in Personal Immortality (1913). 2+pp., undated (Box 3)
  - Hosford, A. H.: Autograph letter signed to Bastian. 1 page, undated (Box 3)
  - Huxley, Henrietta Anne: Autograph letter signed to Bastian. 2 pp., undated (Box 3)
  - John Howard McFadden Research Fund: Autograph document concerning preparation of tyrosine, initialed “J.W.C.” (J. W. Cropper?). 1 page, undated (Box 3)
  - Kebbel, T. S.: Autograph letter signed to Miss Bastian. 2 pp., undated (Box 3)